[
    
    {
        "QorL":"Q",
        "question":"Which among the following is a unicellular organism that reproduces by budding:",
        "options":
        [
            "Hydra",
            "Planaria",
            "Yeast",
            "Spirogyra"
        ],
        "correctAns": "Yeast"
    },
    {
        "QorL":"Q",
        "question":"Planariaâ€™s most remarkable characteristics are its ability to",
        "options":
        [
            "Hibernation",
            "Survive without air",
            "Generate bioluminescence",
            "Regenerate"
        ],
        "correctAns": "Regenerate"
    },
    {
        "QorL":"Q",
        "question":"Bryophyllum can be propagated vegetatively by the",
        "options":
        [
            "Stem",
            "Leaf",
            "Root",
            "Flower"
        ],
        "correctAns": "Leaf"
    },
    {
        "QorL":"Q",
        "question":"In a potato, vegetative propagation takes place by:",
        "options":
        [
            "Root",
            "Leaf",
            "Stem tuber",
            "Grafting"
        ],
        "correctAns": "Stem tuber"
    },
    {
        "QorL":"Q",
        "question":"The transfer of pollen from the anther to stigma is called",
        "options":
        [
            "Pollination",
            "Fertilization",
            "Adoption",
            "Diffusion"
        ],
        "correctAns": "Pollination"
    },
    {
        "QorL":"Q",
        "question":"The male reproductive parts of a flower, the stamens, are collectively known as",
        "options":
        [
            "Androecium",
            "Filament",
            "Anther",
            "Gynoecium"
        ],
        "correctAns": "Androecium"
    },
    {
        "QorL":"Q",
        "question":"How many autosomes does a human primary spermatocyte have?",
        "options":
        [
            "34",
            "44",
            "54",
            "33"
        ],
        "correctAns": "44"
    },
    {
        "QorL":"Q",
        "question":"The _________ is a temporary organ that connects a mammalian mother to its foetus",
        "options":
        [
            "Placenta",
            "Chorion",
            "Endometrium",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "correctAns": "Placenta"
    },
    {
        "QorL":"Q",
        "question":"The cell produced by fertilization is called",
        "options":
        [
            "Gamete",
            "Embryo",
            "Fetus",
            "zygote"
        ],
        "correctAns": "Gamete"
    },
    {
        "QorL":"Q",
        "question":"The average menstrual cycle is",
        "options":
        [
            "14 days",
            "18 days",
            "24 days",
            "28 days"
        ],
        "correctAns": "28 days"
    }
]